Chapter 16. Nasal consonants. Block the air with your tongue and release it
through your nose. We now turn to the three consonants whose sounds come out
through the nose. M, N, and the NG combination. They each have one thing in
common. Their sound is blocked in the mouth in one of three locations. Two of
them, N and NG, you can't even see, as with R, so they're hard to pick up on. M is the
easiest and most obvious, like b. The lips come together and the air can't get out so
it has to come through the nose. N is in a position similar to t, but it can't be at
all tense. It has to be completely relaxed, filling the whole mouth, touching
the insides of all the teeth, leaving no room for the air to escape except by the
nose. NG is back in the throat with G. The back of the tongue presses back and again
the air comes out through the nose.